# Esther Ejidike

#### Contact

59 Agungi Road, Lekki, Lagos, Nigeria

**09070392990** 08020929012

#### **Email**

ejidikeesther@gmail.com

### Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap/MDbootstrap
- Git/Github
- Wordpress
- Rest APIs
- GSAP
- Slack
- Asana

# **Professional Summary**

An enthusiastic front end developer with hands-on experience in creating interactive and responsive web applications, translating designs to front-end code, interacting with Rest APIs, code versioning, and using external libraries to create rich interfaces. Aim is to be part of a team with sound vision that challenges people to be the best that they can.

# Work Experience

07/2020 - present

#### **ITscopesolutions LTD, Lagos**

- · Designing and developing critical web applications
- Building working prototypes at tech scoping stage of projects
- Creating professional emails and setting up email clients
- · Managing hosting and domain platforms
- Configuration of DNS and use of FTP solutions
- Working with designers to build interacting and engaging interfaces
- Liaising with team to provide costing and thorough scanning of RFQs from clients

06/2020 - 08/2020

# **She Code Africa Mentorship Program**

- Learnt with minimum supervision and developed time management skills
- · Built-up researching and technical writing abilities
- Completion of mini-projects to strengthen knowledge of fundamentals
- Application of reactis to encourage comfortable use of external libraries

06/2020 - 07/2020

# **ALCwithMicrosoft Azure Training**

- In-depth understanding of Azure, cloud concepts, services, and terminologies
- Ability to search for core cloud services in the portal and deploy websites successfully
- Learnt how to manage identities, resource groups, apply tags and monitor service health

02/2020 - 03/2020

#### **Developer Circle Training**

- Adopted best practices for writing JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Familiarized with the basics of Reactis
- · Dabbled with Gatsby, the static site generator
- Comfortable use of Frontend libraries such as bootstrap, swiper.js, gsap, wavify, etc

08/2019 - 11/2019

#### **DevC Training with Andela, Lagos**

- Adopted best practices and a mobile-first approach for web development
- Studied project requirements and planned development strategies
- · Made use of task runner (gulp) to automate tasks
- Familiarity with Node package manager, JSON and rest APIs
- Developed ability to research, accept feedback and refactor

08/2019 - 09/2019

#### **Boldtrail Studios, Enugu**

Designed and developed company website from scratch

- Purchased and managed domain and hosting for the site
- · Ensured site security using Cloudflare

04/2019 - 07/2019

# Tony Osime employee training and consulting company, Lagos

- Co-designed managed and monitored the site for continuous development
- Represented tech team at meetings with the executive and other team members
  - Weekly progress report and discussion of project goals and milestones
- Optimized images and web assets for speed, performance and high ranking on the web

#### Education

09/2014 - 06/2018

# **Chukwuemeka Odumegwu Ojukwu University, Anambra state, Nigeria**

- B.Sc. Public Administration Second Class Honours (Upper Division)
- My Portfolio https://queen-esther01.github.io/portfolio/ Github Profile - https://github.com/Queen-esther01)
- Az-900 Microsoft Azure fundamentals (https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LcQF1F\_6GKmMBIUdT5h32NamRKQYIrr T/view?usp=drivesdk)
- Freecodecamp Responsive Web design (https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/king\_esther/responsive-webdesign)

#### Languages

English Language — B2

#### References

Available Upon Request